Finding Aid for Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy (University of Michigan) Records
Bentley Historical Library
- Philippine Institute of Public Administration Project, 1952-1957
  The Philippine Institute of Public Administration Project series (3 linear feet) offers insight into the development of a regional training center for public administration at the University of the Philippines in 1952. The records were created between 1952 and 1957, and include budget materials, correspondence, publicity materials, and other general information. The Reports and the Semi-Annual Reports subseries are especially rich as they include detailed information about projects and the development of the Philippine Institute.
  - Advisory (Box 4)
  - Budget, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Contract (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Curriculum (Box 5)
  - Established Institutes (Box 5)
  - In-Service Training, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - International Cooperation Administration (Box 5)
  - International Cooperation Administration Mission (Box 5)
  - Library (Box 5)
  - Library Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Personnel, General Information (Box 5)
  - Philippine Announcement (Box 5)
  - Post Report (Box 5)
  - Publicity (Box 5)
  - Records Management (Box 5)
  - Reports (Box 5)
  - Reports, Semi-Annual (Box 5)
  - Sister Institutions (Box 5)
  - Trainees, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Trainees, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Training Program, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan Officials (Box 6)
  - University of the Philippines (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Philippine Institute of Public Administration Project – Rededication of Rizal Hall, 1954 February 22; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips (Box 6)
    - [Part 1], [87209-SR-4-1]; (Dedication event to Rizal Hall at the University of the Philippines. Includes several speeches from different speakers.)
      [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
- Taiwan Center for Public and Business Administration Education Project, 1962-1965
  In 1962, the Center for Public and Business Administration was established in Taiwan. The records comprising the Taiwan Center for Public and Business Administration series (2.25 linear feet) describe the establishment of the Center as a joint project between the University of Michigan, the Republic of China, and the Agency for International Aid. This series contains information about the Center's contract and budget, as well as correspondence. The Newspaper Clippings and Articles subseries and the Monthly Team Reports subseries offer researchers both internal and external views of the development of the Taiwan Center for Public and Business Administration.
  - Activity Reports, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - A.I.D. Conferences (Box 6)
  - A.I.D./C-CUSA Budget Reports (Box 6)
  - Amendment No. I (Box 6)
  - Amendment No. II (Box 6)
  - Budget, 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Contract (Box 7)
  - Contract Interpretation File (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Extension (Box 7)
  - Monthly Team Reports (Box 7)
  - News Clippings and Articles (Box 7)
  - Old Manual Orders A.I.D./W (Box 7)
  - Orientation Materials for Taiwan Personnel (Box 7)
  - Pre-Contract General Information (Box 7)
  - Quarterly Financial Report-Chief of Party (Box 7)
  - Seminar on Case Development CPBA Materials (Box 7)
  - Standard Contract of A.I.D. Submitted to President Hatcher (Box 7)
  - Taiwan Summer Survey, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Task Force on A.I.D.-University Relationships (Box 7)
  - Three Party Contract (Box 7)
  - Two Party Contract (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- Michigan Constitutional Convention Files, 1961-1962
  The Michigan Constitutional Convention series (1.75 linear feet) contains information pertaining to the Constitutional Convention called in Michigan in 1961. This was the first Constitutional Convention called in Michigan since 1907. James K. Pollock and other Institute of Public Administration faculty were actively involved in the Constitutional Convention and the Institute published two monographs on the subject. Information about Pollock's activities in the Constitutional Convention, as well as materials pertaining to citizen advisory groups on various topics ranging from taxation to education, are included in this series. Detailed information regarding citizens' views about the revision of the Michigan Constitution is located in the subseries Questionnaires for Con-Con Nominees.
  - James K. Pollock Notes on Con-Con Meetings, 1961-1962; 17 folders (Box 8)
  - Seminar on the New Michigan Constitution of Higher Education, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Questionnaires for Con-Con Nominees, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Study Committee on Constitutional Revision, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Constitutional Convention-Citizens' Advisory Committee on Finance and Taxation (Box 8)
  - Constitutional Convention-Citizens' Advisory Committee on the Executive Department (Box 8)
  - Constitutional Convention-Other Citizens' Advisory Committees (Box 8)
  - Constitutional Convention-Task Force Committee on Education (Box 8)
- Lansing Office Files, 1956-1968
  The series, Lansing Office (1.75 linear feet), is comprised of records created by the Institute of Public Administration's field office located in Lansing, Michigan. These materials were created between 1956 and 1968. The series contains correspondence and budgetary information, as well as information about internships in which students at the Institute participated.
  - American Society for Public Administration (Box 9)
  - Associations, Leagues, Societies, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - General Correspondence, 22 folders (Box 9)
  - Lansing Office, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Research Assistants (Box 9)
  - Student Research Projects, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - University of Michigan, 5 folders (Box 9)
- Chronological Files, 1973-1983
  The Chronological Files series (1 linear foot) contains documentation of the Institute of Public Policy Studies between the years 1973 and 1983. The series is mainly comprised of correspondence, however, applications for grants, memoranda to the faculty from the director, announcements for brown bags, among other items are also located here. Since few topical files for the years spanned by the Chronological Files series are held by the Bentley, the materials in the Chronological Files series offer valuable information about this period.
  - 1973, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 10)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 10)
- Topical Files, 1966-1993
  The Topical Files series (3.5 linear feet) includes records arranged topically by year from 1981 through 1993, except for a group of records which were unordered when they were received and spanned several years. These comprise the 1966-1980 subseries. This subseries contains limited information about the administrative and research activities of the Institute. Files which include exceptional information are the Ann Arbor Political History and the Kidney Problem files. Both of these files include information about faculty research at the Institute of Public Policy Studies. The remaining subseries include information pertaining to the daily activities of the Institute for Public Policy Studies. These include documents about the Institute's curriculum, demographics of its students, visitors, and activities. Files which contain information about the administrative activities at the Institute include the Faculty Memos from the Director files, Executive Committee files, the Student Affairs files, and the Visitors files. They allow for a broad overview of how the Institute of Public Policy Studies developed between 1981 and 1993. More detailed information about topics of particular interest at the Institute is offered by the Brown Bags and Lectures files and the European Growth Project.
  - 1966-1980
    - Ann Arbor Political History, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Association for Public Policy Analysis and Management, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
    - Curriculum and Program Committee, 1969-1973 (Box 10)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee, 1968-1973 (Box 10)
    - Faculty Memos from Director, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Ford Foundation-Public Administration, 1966-1968 (Box 10)
    - J.D./Masters of Public Policy Degree, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
    - Kidney Problem, 1967-1977 (Box 10)
    - Long Range Plans, 1966-1970 (Box 10)
    - Municipal League, 1975-1980; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Off Campus Duty, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Public Systems Engineering Program, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - Personnel Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - Ph. D. Program, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
    - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Program, 1993 (Box 11)
  - 1981-1982
    - Affirmative Action, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Anderson Visit, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Association for Public Policy Analysis Management, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Canadian Conference, 1981-1983 (Box 11)
    - Computer, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Director's Meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Division of Research Development and Administration, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Economics and Public Policy, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Ecole Nationale d'Administration Publique, 1979-1982 (Box 11)
    - Faculty Memos from Director, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Lecture Series, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Municipal League, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Reissert, Berndt, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
    - Student Affairs
      - Aid, 1982 (Box 11)
      - Charts, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Visitors-Actual
      - Barry Blechman, 1981 (Box 11)
      - Juin Han Tsao, 1980-1982 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Visitors-Potential, 1981 (Box 11)
  - 1982-1983
    - Affirmative Action, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Australian Visit, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Brown Bags, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Business School, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - College Resources Analysis System, 1980-1983 (Box 11)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Director's Meetings, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Division of Research Development and Administration, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Economics, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Executive Committee
      - Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 11)
      - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Faculty Memos from Director, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Municipal League, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - National Science Foundation: Gramlich, Courant, Rubinfeld, 1979-1982 (Box 11)
    - Political Science, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Pugwash, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Student Affairs
      - Aid, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
      - Statistics, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Visitors-Actual, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Visitors-Potential, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - 1983-1984
    - Affirmative Action, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Brown Bags and Lectures, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Curriculum, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Economics, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Faculty Memos from Director
      - Faculty Research Statements, 1983 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Faculty/Staff Directory, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - I.D. Cards, 1973-1983 (Box 12)
    - LSA Enrollment Program, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Municipal League, 1984 (Box 12)
    - National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Political Science, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Rackham, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Reports/Questionnaires, 1980-1984 (Box 12)
    - Student Affairs
      - Aid, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
      - International Track, 1983 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
      - Visitors' Committee, undated (Box 12)
    - Sussman Committee, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Visitors-Potential, 1983 (Box 12)
  - 1984-1985
    - Affirmative Action, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Brown Bags and Lectures, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Canadian Conference, 1983-1986 (Box 12)
    - Economics, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Faculty Memos from Director, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Faculty/Staff Directory, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - I.D. Cards, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Lingenfelter, Paul, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Municipal League, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - National Council of University Research Administrators, 1984 (Box 12)
    - National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Political Science, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Trade Policies Conference, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Space, 1976-1985 (Box 12)
    - Student Affairs, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - 1985-1986
    - Affirmative Action, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Alumni Affairs, 1983-1986 (Box 12)
    - American Institutions, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
    - Bureau of Government Library, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
    - Brown Bags and Lectures, 1984-1986 (Box 12)
    - Bush Program, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
    - Business School, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Computers, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Defense Seminar, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Economics, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Ecole Nationale d'Administration Publique, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Faculty Memos from Director, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Foster Library, 1986 (Box 12)
    - International Track, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Lorch Hall, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Peace and Security, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
    - Political Science, 1984-1986 (Box 12)
    - Rackham, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Reports and Questionnaires, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
    - Space, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Student Affairs, 1986-1987 (Box 12)
  - 1986-1987
    - Accelerated Program, 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - Administrative Directives, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Affirmative Action, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Albion College, 1983-1986 (Box 13)
    - Applications, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Brown Bags and Lectures, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Bulletins, undated (Box 13)
    - Canadian Conference, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Computer Instruction, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
    - Curriculum, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
    - Development, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Economics, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - European Growth Project, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Faculty Memos from Director, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Faculty/Staff Directory, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Foster Library, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - I.D. Cards, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Municipal League, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Newsletter, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Political Science, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Presidential Initiatives Fund Proposals, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Reports and Questionnaires, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Shapiro Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 13)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Student Affairs, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Visitors-Actual, undated (Box 13)
  - 1992-1993
    - Alumnae Society, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Twenty-fifth Anniversary Celebration, 1993 (Box 13)
- Sound Recordings, 1964; 1993
  The Sound Recordings series (11 cassette tapes and 3 reel-to-reel tapes) contains recordings of the celebration of the fiftieth anniversary of public administration at the University of Michigan in 1964, also recordings of round tables held at the Institute of Public Policy's twenty-fifth anniversary celebration in 1993.
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Symposium, 1964; 3 Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips (Box 14)
    - [Part 1], [87209-SR-1-1]; (Reel 1; Symposium for the 50th Anniversary of the Institute of Public Administration. John David Millett speaking.)
    - [Reel 2, Part 1], [87209-SR-2-1]; (Reel 2; Symposium for the 50th Anniversary of the Institute of Public Administration. Dr. John William Lederle, President of the University of Massachusetts, A Dr. Reed and other unidentified speakers.)
    - [Reel 3, Part 1], [87209-SR-3-1]; (Reel 3; Symposium for the 50th Anniversary of the Institute of Public Administration. Names referenced include Arthur Mailman, Professor Mackinzie, Amos Halley, and others.)
  - Institute for Public Policy 25th Anniversary Symposium, October 22-23, 1993
    - Opening, October 22, 1993; 2 audiocassettes (101 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Future of the American City, October 22, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (75 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Policy Analyst, Public Manager, Policy Maker?, October 22, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (50 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Reinventing Government, October 22, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (75 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Reinventing U.S. Trade Policy?, October 22, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (75 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Security Issues for the Twenty-First Century, October 22, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (75 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Should Environmental Regulators be Partners or Police?, October 22, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (75 minutes) (Box 14)
    - Healthcare Reform, October 23, 1993; 2 audiocassettes (Box 14)
    - Policy and Politics Roundtable, October 23, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (Box 14)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series (.5 linear feet) contains photographs of faculty, students, and events held at the Institute of Public Policy Studies between the 1952 and 1987. Specific subjects documented include the Institute of Public Administration's Fiftieth Anniversary and the Philippine Institute of Public Administration. Photographs of the Philippine Institute depict students, faculty, and renovation of buildings there.
  - Events, undated
    - Paul Courant with President Jimmy Carter (Box 14)
    - Robert Stearn and Jacques Artus (Box 14)
    - Robert Stearn, Howard Shapiro, Geza Feketekuty, and Mitsuhiro Fukao (Box 14)
  - Faculty, 1986-1987 (Box 14)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Philippine Project, 1952-1955 (Box 14)
  - Students, 1983-1986
    - Entering Students
      - 1982-1983 (Box 14)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 14)
    - Graduates, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Class Picture, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - Student Groups with Drs. Heady and Gable, undated (Box 14)
- Joan and Sanford Weil Hall Groundbreaking and Dedication, 2004-2006
  The Joan and Sanford Weil Hall Groundbreaking and Dedication Series (.5 linear feet) contains the contents of two binders received by the library documenting the groundbreaking ceremony (November 12th, 2004) and dedication ceremony (October 13th, 2006) of the school's new home. Logistics, those invited and attending, speeches delivered, and the publicity and media coverage are well documented for both events. President Gerald R. Ford and family were in attendance at the groundbreaking ceremony. Speeches delivered at the event include an address by University of Michigan President Mary Sue Coleman expressing gratitude for Gerald R. Ford's contributions to the University and the beneficence of Joan and Sanford Weil. President Ford also made some remarks regarding his memories of his undergraduate experience at the University of Michigan and the pioneering work undertaken at the Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy. There are a number of photographs in each of the subseries that have been retained in loco to preserve the context of the visual information.
  - Groundbreaking Ceremony, November 12th, 2004
    - Mailings (Box 18)
      [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2024 ]
    - Budgets (Box 18)
    - Attendance Lists (Box 18)
    - Invitation Lists (Box 18)
    - Seating Charts (Box 18)
    - Meeting Notes (Box 18)
    - Speeches (Box 18)
    - Schedules (Box 18)
    - Accommodations (Box 18)
    - Transportation (Box 18)
    - Weil Question and Answer Session with Students (Box 18)
    - Media Coverage (Box 18)
    - Emergency Phone Numbers (Box 18)
    - Thank You Notes (Box 18)
    - Photographs (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - Dedication, October 13th, 2006
    - Publications (Box 18)
      [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2026 ]
    - Budget (Box 18)
    - Schedules (Box 18)
    - Invitation Lists (Box 18)
    - Attendee Lists (Box 18)
    - Event Logistics (Box 18)
    - Speeches (Box 18)
    - Tours (Box 18)
    - Meeting Notes (Box 18)
    - Accommodations (Box 18)
    - Transportation (Box 18)
    - Media Coverage (Box 18)
    - Phone List (Box 18)
    - Photographs (Box 18)
    - Thank You Notes (Box 18)
    - Clippings (Box 18)
- Archived Website
  The Archived Website series (2002-2008, 3.78 GB; 2010-[ONGOING]) documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Ford School of Public Policy as presented on its public website. Content includes important news and announcements, publications including newsletters, course catalogs, and working papers, and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, student life, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. The series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1997 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists in 2002, 2003, 2006, and 2008. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
  - Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy
    - 1997
      (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - 1998-2002
    - 2001-[ONGOING]
    - May 15, 2002, .ZIP file
    - May 22, 2003, .ZIP file
    - March 16, 2006, .ZIP file
    - May 8-9, 2008, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Related resources
    - 2010-[ONGOING]